Guide to Speeches in the Records of the Office of the President (Dr. John Brademas) RG 3.0.10
New York University Archives
- Series I
  - Remarks delivered at the Graduate School of Business Administration Annual Alumni Awards Dinner, NYU Club, 13 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 12)
  - Remarks delivered at a University Senate Meeting, NYU, 14 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 13)
  - Remarks delivered at the Friends of Town Hall Award Dinner, NYU Club, 17 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 14)
  - Report before the Board of Trustees, NYU, 18 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 15)
  - Introductory remarks regarding an award for Governor Carey presented at the NYU School of Law Alumni Day, 23 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 16)
  - Remarks delivered before the Executive Committee of the Faculty Council, NYU, 21 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 17)
  - Parents' Day, NYU, 24 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 18)
  - Remarks at the opening session of the National Forum of the College Board, 27 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 19)
  - The Fifth Avenue Association, 27 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 20)
  - Dental Associates Dinner, 27 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 21)
  - Ex-Cell-O Reception at the School of Graduate Business Administration, 28 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 22)
  - Remarks delivered at an Archbishop Iakovos High School Dinner (Jamaica, NY), 29 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 23)
  - Greek High School Parents Conference, St. Demetrios High School (Astoria, NY), 30 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 24)
  - Louis Marshall Memorial Dinner, Jewish Theological Seminary, 31 October 1982 (Box 614, Folder 25)
  - Remarks by Laurence Tisch and John Brademas at the Tisch School of the Arts Faculty Convocation, 1 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 26)
  - Council on International Education Annual Conference, NYU, 3 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 27)
  - Charles Waldo Haskins Associates Dinner, 8 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 28)
  - Remarks before a meeting of the Board of Trustees of the Institute of Fine Arts, NYU, 8 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 29)
  - "Pressure Group Attacks on Free Speech," 92nd St. Y & NY Civil Liberties Union, 9 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 30)
  - Remarks before the NYU Alumnae Club, Woman of Achievement Award (presented to Grace Glueck), NYU, 9 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 31)
  - Talking points for meeting of the Executive Committee of the Faculty Council, 10 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 32)
  - Remarks before the University Senate, 11 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 33)
  - Remarks delivered before an award presentation for Dr. Oliva, NYU Alumni Association of Southern California (Los Angeles, CA), 13 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 34)
  - John Sessions Memorial Award Presentation, Robert Wagner Archives, NYU, 17 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 35)
  - Remarks delivered at the inauguration of Jonathan Fanton as president of the New School, 18 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 36)
  - Remarks regarding Arthur T. Vanderbilt, delivered before the Institute of Judical Administration Dinner, 18 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 37)
  - Remarks relating to a proposed Japanese Center at NYU, Keidanren Kaikan (Tokyo, Japan), 22 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 38)
  - Remarks delivered at a reception for Japanese alumni, NYU, 22 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 39)
  - Remarks on library resources delivered at a Dean's lunch honoring Phillip Johnson & Richard Foster, NYU, 29 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 40)
  - Foreword to the student financial aid handbook, 29 November 1982 (Box 614, Folder 41)
  - Remarks on the handicapped for the Blum Presidential Citation at the School of Education, NYU, 1 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 42)
  - Remarks delivered at the Commerce Dean's Day, NYU, 4 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 43)
  - Seldin Letter for Dr. Brademas, 9 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 44)
  - Remarks delivered before the Christmas tree lighting in Washington Square, 9 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 45)
  - Speech delivered before the Tisch School of the Arts, 9 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 46)
  - Speech delivered by Dean Oppenheim, Tisch School of the Arts, 9 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 47)
  - Memorandum from Dr. Brademas to the Domestic Policy Study Group Center for National Policy, 10 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 48)
  - Remarks on Dr. Fritz Machlup at a reception for Dr. Machlup by the Department of Economics, 14 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 49)
  - Remarks at a reception for Leon Shimkin, NYU, 14 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 50)
  - Remarks delivered to the Executive Committee of the Faculty Council, NYU, 16 December 1982 (Box 614, Folder 51)
  - Review of Congress and the Common Goo d, by Arthur Maas, 1983 (Box 614, Folder 52)
  - Remarks on Fulbright programs on the 35th Anniversary of the Fulbright Program in Greece (Athens, Greece), 12 January 1983 (Box 614, Folder 53)
  - Remarks delivered during Advisory Council Executive Management Training in Athens Program (Athens, Greece), 13 January 1983 (Box 614, Folder 54)
  - Remarks delivered by Larry Tisch at the Federal Reserve Dinner, 19 January 1983 (Box 614, Folder 55)
  - Remarks delivered before the New York Federal Executive Board, 19 January 1983 (Box 614, Folder 56)
  - Radio interview about the Education Commission (WCBS), 19 January 1983 (Box 614, Folder 57)
  - Humphrey Award, Metropolitan Social Studies Conference, 22 January 1983 (Box 615, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042254626
  - Remarks delivered at the presentation of a citation to Badinter (NYU), 22 January 1983 (Box 615, Folder 2)
  - Remarks at Universal Studios Dinner Honoring Dr. Brademas (Los Angeles), 27 January 1983 (Box 615, Folder 3)
  - Remarks by Preston R. Tisch at dinner honoring Dr. Brademas (Los Angeles), 27 January 1983 (Box 615, Folder 4)
  - Remarks delivered before the Southern California Association for Philanthropy (Los Angeles), 28 January 1983 (Box 615, Folder 5)
  - Remarks delivered at the Alumni Federation Board of Directors Meeting (NYU Club), 1 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 6)
  - Draft statement on registration & student aid (NYU), 2 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 7)
  - Remarks delivered before the Graduate School of Public Administration, NYU, 3 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 8)
  - Remarks delivered before the University Senate, NYU, 10 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 10)
  - Remarks delivered before the Touche Ross Roundtable/Mgt of Higher Education (NYC), 14 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 11)
  - Remarks delivered before the Executive Committee of the Faculty Council (NYU), 15 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 12)
  - Talking points on Claude Montana/Bergdorf Benefit for the Grey Art Gallery, 15 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 13)
  - Remarks delivered at a press conference about the resumption of men's varsity basketball at NYU, 17 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 14)
  - Belfer Luncheon (Palm Beach, FL), 20 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 15)
  - Remarks delivered at a dinner honoring Dean Stedman (NYU), 24 February 1983 (Box 615, Folder 16)
  - Remarks delivered at the LBJ Symposium commemorating FDR's 50th Anniversary (University of Texas), 4 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 17)
  - Gallatin Vice-Chairmen & Deans Breakfast, NYU, 7 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 18)
  - Cunningham Arts & Salute Dinner (NYC), 7 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 19)
  - Remarks delivered at a luncheon announcing the new development campaign, NYU, 8 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 20)
  - Remarks by Oliva, Tisch, and Heyman, delivered at a press conference announcing the new fundraising campaign, 8 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 21)
  - New Fundraising Luncheon, NYU, 8 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 22)
  - Remarks delivered before the University Senate, NYU, 10 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 23)
  - Welcome remarks delivered at "The Making of Foreign Policy," a Haig Public Policy lecture, 10 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 24)
  - Remarks delivered at the NEA Higher Education Conference (Washington, D.C.), 11 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 25)
  - Remarks on war, peace & the news media, NYU, 18 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 27)
  - Remarks delivered at a conference of GBA alumni, NYU, 19 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 28)
  - Remarks delivered at the launch for Catalan Week at NYU, 21 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 29)
  - Remarks delivered at the dedication of the Kaplan Cancer Center, NYU Medical Center, 22 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 30)
  - Remarks delivered at a dinner for Altshuler, NYU, 24 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 31)
  - Colloquium on Catalonia in Modern Spain, 24 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 32)
  - Remarks delivered at the City Club of New York, CUNY Graduate Center, 25 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 33)
  - Remarks delivered at the Archons of the Ecumenical Patriarchate Annual Banquet (NYC), 26 March 1983 (Box 615, Folder 34)
  - Remarks delivered at a reception for Professor Gay Wilson Allen, 4 April 1983 (Box 615, Folder 35)
  - Joseph Lubin Memorial, 7 April 1983 (Box 615, Folder 36)
  - Rabbi Morris Lieberman Memorial Lecture, Baltimore Hebrew Congregation, 23 April 1983 (Box 615, Folder 37)
  - Recording for the Blind Awards, Yale Club, 27 April 1983 (Box 615, Folder 38)
  - Giscard d'Estaing Lecture, NYU, 27 April 1983 (Box 615, Folder 39)
  - Great Teacher Awards, NYU, 28 April 1983 (Box 615, Folder 40)
  - "Sailing Against the Wind," delivered at the Boston University Conference on Arts & Education, 29 April 1983 (Box 615, Folder 41)
  - Remarks delivered before the University Senate, 5 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 42)
  - James C. Finlay Higher Education Commission, NY State Assembly, 6 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 43)
  - "Public & Private Sectors," delivered before the GPA Alumni Association, NYU, 9 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 44)
  - American Jewish Committee Dinner Bestowing the Herbert H. Lehman Award on Martin Lipton (NYC), 10 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 46)
  - Remarks delivered before the Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York (NYC), 10 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 47)
  - "Engaging a Whole World: The Humanities in the 1980s," delivered as part of the President's Forum at Claremont University (Claremont, CA), 13 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 48)
  - Commencement address delivered at Claremont Graduate University (Claremont, CA), 14 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 49)
  - Remarks delivered at a dinner honoring Dean Griffiths, NYU Club, 20 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 50)
  - Reagan Remarks at Seton Hall University (South Orange, NJ), 21 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 51)
  - Commencement address delivered at SUNY-Albany, 22 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 52)
  - Remarks at the dedication of the third floor, Bobst Library, 23 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 53)
  - Annual Alumni Dinner, NYU Club, 24 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 54)
  - Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, 24 May 1983 (Box 615, Folder 55)
  - Remarks delivered at the Pre-Commencement Dinner for the Board of Trustees, NYU, 2 June 1983 (Box 615, Folder 57)
  - Welcome remarks delivered at the School of Medicine commencement, 2 June 1983 (Box 615, Folder 58)
  - Remarks delivered at the all-University commencement, 3 June 1983 (Box 615, Folder 59)
  - Commencement address at Lowell (Lowell, MA), 4 June 1983 (Box 615, Folder 60)
  - Remarks delivered before National State Budget Officers (Albany, NY), 7 June 1983 (Box 615, Folder 61)
  - Eastern Regional Conference of National State Budget Officers (Albany, NY), 7 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042254634
  - Introductory remarks for Claiborne Pell (Washington, D.C.), 9 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 2)
  - Remarks delivered before a meeting of the Congressional Intern Program (Washington, D.C.), 9 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 3)
  - Shady Side Academy Commencement, 10 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 4)
  - Rev. Boardman W. Kathan, NYU, 14 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 5)
  - Remarks delivered at a Life Gallatin Reception, NYU, 14 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 6)
  - Remarks delivered before Omicron Kappa Epsilon (NYC), 15 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 7)
  - Introduction to Duel for the Dunes, a book by Schaeffer and Franklin, 23 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 8)
  - Communications Technology in Education & Training, 27 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 9)
  - Remarks delivered at Birkbeck College, London, 30 June 1983 (Box 616, Folder 10)
  - Lifelong Learning Leaders Retreat Report, 1 July 1983 (Box 616, Folder 11)
  - International Education in U.S., 7 July 1983 (Box 616, Folder 12)
  - Graduate Education Hearing, 7 July 1983 (Box 616, Folder 13)
  - French-American Foundation Dinner, 18 July 1983 (Box 616, Folder 14)
  - High School for the Humanities Project, 25 July 1983 (Box 616, Folder 15)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures Annual Meeting, 9 August 1983 (Box 616, Folder 16)
  - New York Times article draft, 12 August 1983 (Box 616, Folder 17)
  - Article for Design magazine, 15 August 1983 (Box 616, Folder 18)
  - Speech about the Kennedy assassination, August 1983 (Box 616, Folder 19)
  - Student Convocation, 12 September 1983 (Box 616, Folder 20)
  - BOBCAT Press Conference, 15 September 1983 (Box 616, Folder 22)
  - Montclair State College 75th Anniversary, 20 September 1983 (Box 616, Folder 23)
  - Inaugural Symposium of the Indiana University Instititute for Advanced Study (Bloomington, IN), 26 September 1983 (Box 616, Folder 24)
  - All-University Graduate Student Reception, 28 September 1983 (Box 616, Folder 25)
  - Press conference, IFA, 29 September 1983 (Box 616, Folder 26)
  - Reception for Stephen Chan at IFA, September 30. 1983 (Box 616, Folder 27)
  - The Cosmetic, Toiletry and Fragrance Association Luncheon, 30 September 1983 (Box 616, Folder 28)
  - 35th Annual Conference of Association of Graduate Schools, 3 October 1983 (Box 616, Folder 29)
  - Gallatin Associates Dinner, 6 October 1983 (Box 616, Folder 30)
  - 2nd Annual Faculty Convocation, Bobst Library, 11 October 1983 (Box 616, Folder 31)
  - Penthouse Dinner for Father Hesburgh, 17 October 1983 (Box 616, Folder 32)
  - Accountants Club of America Luncheon, 27 October 1983 (Box 616, Folder 34)
  - Remarks delivered at the International Relations Study Center, 27 October 1983 (Box 616, Folder 35)
  - Welcome remarks delivered at the Modern Greek Symposium, NYU, 27 October 1983 (Box 616, Folder 36)
  - Remarks delivered before the Association of Independent Colleges & Universities (NJ), 28 October 1983 (Box 616, Folder 37)
  - Parents' Day Receptions, NYU, 6 November 1983 (Box 616, Folder 38)
  - Trustees Scholars Dinner, NYU, 9 November 1983 (Box 616, Folder 39)
  - Welcome remarks at the Chet Huntley Memorial Lecture Dinner, NYU, 10 November 1983 (Box 616, Folder 40)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Ceremony, NYU, 17 November 1983 (Box 616, Folder 41)
  - Atlantic Institute for Intn'l Affairs (Washington, D.C.), 18 November 1983 (Box 616, Folder 42)
  - Cyprus Childrens Fund Dinner (NYC), 18 November 1983 (Box 616, Folder 43)
  - Remarks on high schools & universities (Washington), 22 November 1983 (Box 616, Folder 44)
  - Welcome remarks at the Lubin Lecture, Dean's Day at the School of Business and Public Administration, NYU, 3 December 1983 (Box 616, Folder 45)
  - Welcome remarks by Dr. Brademas and Mr. Tisch, convocation honoring the King of Spain, NYU, 6 December 1983 (Box 616, Folder 46)
  - "The Road after 1984: High Tech & Human Freedom," delivered at the Smithsonian Institution, 8 December 1983 (Box 616, Folder 47)
  - Smithsonian Symposium, National Museum of American History, 8 December 1983 (Box 616, Folder 48)
  - Faculty Network Press Conference & Board Meeting, NYU, 13 December 1983 (Box 616, Folder 49)
  - Article for Change magazine, 13 January 1984 (Box 616, Folder 50)
  - Upward Bound Press Conference (NYC), 24 January 1984 (Box 616, Folder 51)
  - Little Forum's Annual Dinner (NYC), 26 January 1984 (Box 616, Folder 52)
  - Annual Midwinter Conference of the New York State Council of School Superintendents (Albany, NY), 29 January 1984 (Box 616, Folder 53)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Centennial Videotape (NYC), 6 February 1984 (Box 616, Folder 54)
  - Graduate & Professional Financial Aid Council (VA), 14 February 1984 (Box 616, Folder 55)
  - Japanese Chamber of Commerce of NY Lunch (NY), 23 February 1984 (Box 616, Folder 56)
  - Dinner honoring Dr. Robert M. Warner, NYU, 23 February 1984 (Box 616, Folder 57)
  - Introductory remarks delivered at a dinner honoring new trustees, NYU, 28 February 1984 (Box 616, Folder 58)
  - Opening Dinner for Picasso Exhibit (NYC), 29 February 1984 (Box 616, Folder 59)
  - "Afternoon at Washington Square" remarks, 4 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 60)
  - Society of Foreign Consuls (NY), 4 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 61)
  - Remarks delivered at a University Senate meeting, NYU, 8 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 62)
  - Trustees-Faculty Council Reception, NYU, 12 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 63)
  - Remarks delivered before presidents, vice presidents, and deans of education from public and independent universities in New York, 13 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 64)
  - Real Estate Institute Annual Urban Leadership Award Dinner, NYU, 14 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 65)
  - Conference on Education: Action for Interaction (CT), 15 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 66)
  - Fuqua/Wright Lunch (Washington, D.C.), 14 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 67)
  - Talking points for Public Affairs Forum PH Dinner, NYU, 15 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 68)
  - Welcome remarks at the Middle States dinner, NYU, 18 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 69)
  - Dean Taggart Memorial, NYU, 21 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 70)
  - Remarks delivered at the Insititute of Environmental Medicine, NYU, 23 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 71)
  - J. Edward Farnum Public Lecture at the Woodrow Wilson School of Public & International Affairs, Princeton University (NJ), 26 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 72)
  - Brief remarks delivered at a lunch honoring Caroline & Joseph S. Gruss Visiting Professorship in Talmudic Law, NYU, 28 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 73)
  - Testimony at a Hearing of the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education Committee on Education & Labor (Washington, D.C.), 29 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 74)
  - Introductory remarks delivered at the Harold Weill Medal Presentation Dinner, NYU, 28 March 1984 (Box 616, Folder 75)
  - Interview with Zubin Mehta, Gallatin Division Great Artist Series, NYU, 4 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 76)
  - Remarks at the dedication & dinner for Ruth and George Farkas Auditorium of Alumni Hall, NYU, 10 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 77)
  - Talking points for remarks delivered at a dinner honoring Frank Todman, NYU, 11 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 78)
  - Welcome remarks delivered before a lunch honoring the warden of Nuffield College (Brock), NYU, Apr 12, 1984 (Box 616, Folder 79)
  - Dinner honoring Maestro Andres Segovia, 14 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 80)
  - National University Continuing Education Association Annual Conference (GA), 17 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 81)
  - Remarks delivered at the presentation of "Award of Honor" medals from Fine Arts Federation of NY to NYU, 18 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 82)
  - Talking points for remarks delivered at a dinner honoring Nicholas Wahl, NYU, 18 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 83)
  - Talking points for remarks delivered at a reception for alumni of the University Heights campus, NYU, 19 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 84)
  - Brief remarks delivered at an executive briefing on the Ada computer language & compiler, Courant Institute, NYU, 23 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 85)
  - Brief remarks delivered at a seminar and dinner honoring Raymond Carr, NYU, 23-25 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 86)
  - Remarks delivered before the NYS Regional Economists Society (NY), 24 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 87)
  - Brief remarks delivered at Founders Day, NYU, 26 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 88)
  - Sermon delivered at a Holocaust remembrance service, NYU, 26 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 89)
  - Remarks delivered at a Mayors Forum on Urban Policy, NYU, 27 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 90)
  - Phi Kappa Phi Induction Ceremony (FL), 27 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 91)
  - Commencement address, University of West Florida (FL), 28 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 92)
  - Westside Community Conference (NY), 29 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 93)
  - Remarks delivered before the faculty of the School of Medicine, NYU, 30 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 94)
  - Article in Grants magazine, 30 April 1984 (Box 616, Folder 95)
  - Jornadas Catalanas seminar on "Ideology/Politics", Spanish Institute, 2 May 1984 (Box 616, Folder 96)
  - Remarks delivered before a meeting of the NYS Association for Supervision & Curriculum Development (NY), 6 May 1984 (Box 616, Folder 97)
  - Annual Alumni Dinner, NYU, 15 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 2)
    bar code: 3 1142 042254642
  - Reception for Israeli poet Amichai, NYU, 16 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 3)
  - 25-Year Service Awards, NYU, 16 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 4)
  - Remarks delivered before a lecture by and dinner honoring Sidney Hook, NYU, 17 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 5)
  - Global Crossroads Panel (Washington, D.C.), 18 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 6)
  - Commencement address, Drew University (NJ), 19 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 7)
  - Cocktail reception honoring new life members of the Albert Gallatin Associates, NYU, 21 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 8)
  - Presentation of citations to honorary degree recipients, Board of Trustees Dinner, NYU, 23 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 9)
  - Remarks delivered at NYU all-University commencement, 24 May 1984 (Box 617, Folder 10)
  - Brief remarks delivered at a cocktail reception honoring Dean William F. May, Graduate School of Business Administration, NYU, 7 June 1984 (Box 617, Folder 11)
  - Albert Gallatin Fellows Dinner, NYU, 7 June 1984 (Box 617, Folder 12)
  - Luncheon of the Propeller Club of the United States (Athens), 12 June 1984 (Box 617, Folder 13)
  - "Current Trends in American Education: A Panoramic View," delivered at the Annual Alumni Day of Athens College (Athens), 12 June 1984 (Box 617, Folder 14)
  - Commencement address, American Community Schools of Athens, 12 June 1984 (Box 617, Folder 15)
  - Ecumenical Doxology homily, New York, 4 July 1984 (Box 617, Folder 16)
  - Ecumenical Doxology Celebration of Independence Day, New York, 4 July 1984 (Box 617, Folder 17)
  - Local 23-25, ILGWU College Textbook Scholarship Awards Ceremony (NY), 16 August 1984 (Box 617, Folder 18)
  - Brief remarks on accepting the American Political Science Association's Hubert H. Humphrey Award (Washington, D.C.), 30 August 1984 (Box 617, Folder 19)
  - "The Research University, Graduate Education and Public Policy", Indiana University, 1 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 20)
  - NYU/Scholastic Ins. Press Conference, 10 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 21)
  - Welcome remarks delivered at the " Brown Plus Thirty" Banquet, NYU, 12 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 22)
  - Student Convocation, NYU, 13 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 23)
  - Brief remarks delivered at the Planned Giving Seminar, NYU, 13 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 24)
  - Brief remarks delivered at the Washington Square Park Crafts & Antiques Fair (NY), 22 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 25)
  - Urban Research Center Luncheon, NYU, 24 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 26)
  - Welcome remarks delivered at a symposium honoring Father Hehir, NYU, 24 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 27)
  - Brief remarks delivered at the Graduate Student Orientation, NYU, 25 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 28)
  - Talking points for remarks delivered at the presentation of Garrigues (Grass Rain), NYU-Spain Institute, 25 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 29)
  - Holy Trinity Cathedral Lecture, New York, 26 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 30)
  - Welcome remarks at a visit of Central American rectors, NYU, 26 September 1984 (Box 617, Folder 31)
  - Accent magazine article, 1 October 1984 (Box 617, Folder 32)
  - Daedalus interview, 1 October 1984 (Box 617, Folder 33)